<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://qzgao.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://qzgao.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-01-07T17:26:07+00:00</updated><id>https://qzgao.github.io/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Moon Catcher</title><subtitle>“The world is hard and cruel. We are here none knows why, and we go none knows whither. We must be very humble. We must see the beauty of quietness. We must go through life so inconspicuously that Fate does not notice us. And let us seek the love of simple, ignorant people. Their ignorance is better than all our knowledge. Let us be silent, content in our little corner, meek and gentle like them. That is the wisdom of life.” ― Maugham</subtitle><author><name>Qiqi Gao</name></author><entry><title type="html">Book Review: *The Catcher in the Rye*</title><link href="https://qzgao.github.io/blog/2024/01/07/book-review-the-catcher-in-the-rye.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Review: *The Catcher in the Rye*" /><published>2024-01-07T09:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-07T09:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://qzgao.github.io/blog/2024/01/07/book-review-the-catcher-in-the-rye</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://qzgao.github.io/blog/2024/01/07/book-review-the-catcher-in-the-rye.html"><![CDATA[<p>My initial reading of <em>The Catcher in the Rye</em> left me quite astonished: it is a book filled with a great amount of slang and profanity. Narrated in the first person perspective and through the voice of the protagonist Holden Caulfield, the book recounts what Holden observes and hears in three days, encompassing his confusion, reflection, and growth. Holden evolves from a state of long-term repression and mental breakdown, where he “got pretty run-down and had to come out here and take it easy” three days prior, to finally seeing himself clearly and wishing to become “the catcher in the rye.” After reading it, I was moved and saddened. It seems that this book is not as it appears on the surface, and it inspired me beyond just “how we look at the ‘lost generation.’” Upon reflection, perhaps the attitude of “lying flat (躺平)” among the young generation in China is also a form of “falling apart.”</p>

<p>Speaking of the “lost generation,” the book indeed doesn’t shy away from criticizing the American society of the 1950s and 1960s. Holden in the book hates school, “All those Ivy League bastards look alike… I swear, I wouldn’t go to one of those Ivy League colleges, if I was dying, for God’s sake.” “It’s full of phonies, and all you do is study so that you can learn enough to be smart enough to be able to buy a goddam Cadillac some day, and you have to keep making believe you give a damn if the football team loses, and all you do is talk about girls and liquor and sex all day, and everybody sticks together in these dirty little goddam cliques.” These are indeed the dark sides of American schools. Well, utilitarianism is not exclusive to American schools; it’s just how our society works.</p>

<p>Holden is also affected by societal repression and even consults a psychiatrist; his inner confusion turns into deep anxiety and fear in his dreariness: “Sometimes I horse around quite a lot, just to keep from getting bored. What I did was, I pulled the old peak of my hunting hat around to the front, then pulled it way down over my eyes. That way, I couldn’t see a goddam thing. ‘I think I’m going blind,’ I said in this very hoarse voice. ‘Mother darling, everything’s getting so dark in here.’”</p>

<p>This descent could not continue; like a simmering soup bound to boil over, Holden ultimately decides to make a change. Or rather, his act of running away from home is a rebellion against his past self. Smoking, drinking, flirting, dancing — after experiencing all these, he realizes, aren’t these the very indulgence and decadence he criticized? It seems that, compared to Mr. Antolini’s preachings, hands-on practices are what truly made Holden better understand the absurdity of his actions.</p>

<p>Holden’s mental world is filled with negative emotions: hesitation, wandering, fear; yet, he is not an ignorant “bad kid.” He loves his family, especially adores his sister, and the book’s ultimate redemption is driven by this familial love. He values friendship, is kind and upright, and out of fear of failing his teacher, he even writes a short letter to console him. Intelligent and critical, he often steps out of the box to see the essence, like his view on those who “like to play the teacher”: “These intellectual guys don’t like to have an intellectual conversation with you unless they’re running the whole thing. They always want you to shut up when they shut up, and go back to your room when they go back to their room.”</p>

<p>—Thinking this way, his confusion and indecisiveness might be his main problem: disliking and unwilling to conform, yet powerless to change. Ha, as if the environment is so easy to change; compromise, return home, integrate into society, perhaps these are the inevitable paths for every rebellious teenager. Holden doesn’t know what he wants, shows no interest in the interests and lives of his peers, does nothing, and has no goals. Of course, this matches the broader context; in an era of indulgence and laziness, unwilling to play the persona set for oneself, what else can one do? Such an overly idealistic Holden, childish yet, is also very sympathetic.</p>

<p>Holden loves his sister Phoebe the most. Whether it’s his feelings of loneliness and confusion or his plans to run away from home, he confides in Phoebe. The time spent with his sister is when his heart is at its most tender and vulnerable. When Holden sees swear words written on the walls of Phoebe’s school, he repeatedly tries to erase them but feels powerless to stop the continuous new graffiti; just like that graffitied wall, we can’t escape the world and values we live in, and such helplessness adds to his pain. He wishes to be a “catcher in the rye,” silently guarding the innocence and beauty within, hoping to change the world with his own strength, to protect his loved ones, to protect the children: “Anyway, I keep picturing all these little kids playing some game in this big field of rye and all. Thousands of little kids, and nobody’s around—nobody big, I mean—except me. And I’m standing on the edge of some crazy cliff. What I have to do, I have to catch everybody if they start to go over the cliff—I mean if they’re running and they don’t look where they’re going I have to come out from somewhere and catch them. That’s all I’d do all day. I’d just be the catcher in the rye and all. I know it’s crazy, but that’s the only thing I’d really like to be. I know it’s crazy.” However, loneliness is a shadow in the heart of the “catcher” that he can’t step beyond. When he’s almost out of money, and Phoebe offers him her Christmas gift money, he can’t hold on anymore and cries uncontrollably: “Then, all of a sudden, I started to cry. I couldn’t help it. I did it so nobody could hear me, but I did it. It scared hell out of old Phoebe when I started doing it, and she came over and tried to make me stop, but once you get started, you can’t just stop on a goddam dime. I was still sitting on the edge of the bed when I did it, and she put her old arm around my neck, and I put my arm around her, too, but I still couldn’t stop for a long time.”</p>

<p>What Holden wants to protect is the innocence of children and the simple, sincere emotions deep within his own heart. This feeling peaks when Phoebe rides the carousel in the amusement park, rotating round and round, while he watches her in the rain, motionless, feeling happy, warm, and satisfied, like an old father. His current state, past, and future, which he is powerless to change, also need not be changed. Just as life must go on; just as he still wishes to be a lonely “catcher in the rye.”</p>

<p>Closing the book, I look back and realize that this confusion and helplessness have always resonated strongly with me. This resonance isn’t about living in an era of materialism; it’s like the news about “top students from renowned universities competing for a job as local community’s civil servants” (civil servants in China are petty, yet corrupt and wealthy) — perhaps “involution” (內卷) is the worry of our generation, at least in today’s China. But this anxiety is not unmanageable; finding something you love, doing a job you are passionate about, may be enough to satisfy. Choose your own path in life, less comparing, and live a peaceful life. “Lying flat” moderately is for a better, and more pleasant way of living.</p>

<p>Until the end of the book, Holden still hasn’t “found his way.” But what are we, the readers, expecting? What is the “right path,” the “road to success”? If one is neither willing to conform to the times, “live humble for it,” nor has the power to rebel, escape, or resist, what then? … At least, by the end of the story, Holden gradually shows us the beginnings of deconstructing and then constructing his own worldview. Perhaps we still hope for “growing up,” for time to smooth out the edges, for our protagonist to slowly reconcile with the times and himself amidst the bitterness and joy of life, to love himself, love the people around him, and continue to be the “catcher in the rye.”</p>]]></content><author><name>Qiqi Gao</name></author><category term="book-review" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My initial reading of The Catcher in the Rye left me quite astonished: it is a book filled with a great amount of slang and profanity. Narrated in the first person perspective and through the voice of the protagonist Holden Caulfield, the book recounts what Holden observes and hears in three days, encompassing his confusion, reflection, and growth. Holden evolves from a state of long-term repression and mental breakdown, where he “got pretty run-down and had to come out here and take it easy” three days prior, to finally seeing himself clearly and wishing to become “the catcher in the rye.” After reading it, I was moved and saddened. It seems that this book is not as it appears on the surface, and it inspired me beyond just “how we look at the ‘lost generation.’” Upon reflection, perhaps the attitude of “lying flat (躺平)” among the young generation in China is also a form of “falling apart.”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New place to record my reading notes</title><link href="https://qzgao.github.io/blog/2024/01/05/new-place-to-record-my-reading-notes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New place to record my reading notes" /><published>2024-01-05T08:53:39+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-05T08:53:39+00:00</updated><id>https://qzgao.github.io/blog/2024/01/05/new-place-to-record-my-reading-notes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://qzgao.github.io/blog/2024/01/05/new-place-to-record-my-reading-notes.html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, I’ve decided to start a blog, mainly to publish my reading notes.</p>

<p>“The world is hard and cruel. We are here none knows why, and we go none knows whither. We must be very humble. We must see the beauty of quietness. We must go through life so inconspicuously that Fate does not notice us. And let us seek the love of simple, ignorant people. Their ignorance is better than all our knowledge. Let us be silent, content in our little corner, meek and gentle like them. That is the wisdom of life.”
  ― W. Somerset Maugham, <em>The Moon and Sixpence</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Qiqi Gao</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well, I’ve decided to start a blog, mainly to publish my reading notes.]]></summary></entry></feed>